Supporting Statement -

Parth Vyas

Dear Sir / Madam,

I believe that I have all the skills required to be successful for this challenging position. I have excellent experience of working within different settings, projects and client facing role. My experience has provided me with an appreciation for working in extremely complex and demanding environment such as 'National Health Services' London, UK and helped me improve my level of confidence in public dealings. I have real passion for Customer service and Operations (good experience of serving multicultural people from across the world), proven by both my experience and research. I am a person who relishes working as a part of the team and contributing best towards achievements. I am a fast learner who can develop new skills quickly, having superior experience of working in multidisciplinary teams, can fit well in any team with confidence, flexibility and adaptability. Besides, I have good ability to resolve conflict in logical and analytical manner.

I am looking forward to utilise the skills I have gained through my academic and professional experience and begin flourish in a new and sustained career whilst keen to expanding and growing my knowledge.

I sincerely believe that my knowledge, experience, education and strong will power would make me eligible candidate for this challenging and exciting opportunity.

Sincerely,

Parth

Parth Bhargav Vyas

+91 – 9909333708 parthvyas18@gmail.com

EDUCATION

GLOBAL MBA (65.5%)

Masters of Business Administration (2013-14) London Metropolitan University, London.

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA STRATEGIC MANAGEMENT & LEADERSHIP

ED-EXCEL BTEC (Level-7) EXTENDED (2011-12) London School of Business and Finance (LSBF), London.

Bachelor of Commerce

Honours in Marketing (2004-07) Bhavnagar University, Gujarat, India.

EMPLOYMENT

Manager – Operations

Tricolour Hospitals, Baroda, Gujarat, India (October 2017 - Present)

Serving as Manager Operations for the hospital, reporting directly to the CEO Sir, monitoring, developing and maintaining all operational requirements. Overseeing the general functioning of the hospital facility. Active participation in implementing policies. Managing clinical and non-clinical staff. Analysing trends and performance through the statistics for betterment of services and procedures. Closely monitoring feedback from service users and colleagues to present the same to the management team to analyse the satisfaction and quality Indices.

- Liaising and coordinating with all hospital departments, clinical and nonclinical ensuring smooth functioning of daily activities.
- Daily operations of the Security, Housekeeping, Patient care attendants, Ambulance and transport facility.

- maintenance department (including HVAC, BMS, Medical gases, Air & vacuum, Civil & General maintenance, PPM schedules, power consumption).
- Promotional and marketing activities and liaising with marketing team, ensuring smooth coordination of corporate relations.
- SOPs and Policy preparation, implementation and monitoring quality indicators as per the standards of NABH.
- Employee & Patient Education programmes and training schedules.
- · Statutory Approvals and Licensing.
- Closely monitoring feedback from service users and colleagues to present the same to the management team to analyse the satisfaction and quality Indices.
- Ensuring confidentiality and integrity of the healthcare facility.
- Regular visits and written communication with corporate clients, meetings for the concerns including payments, patient comfort and closure of the queries before end date.
- Closely monitoring cash and credit billing departments. Making sure the processes are being done as per set SOPs of the organization.
- Responsible for providing adequate support and resources to ensure trouble-free operations of the departments. (IPD, OPD, Diagnostic, Facility, Security).
- Conduct daily, weekly and monthly review meetings with operation teams to review performance, GAPs of previous month, targets for the new month and forming action plans for better outcomes.
- Ensuring quality of services given are equivalent to the set standards, analysing the GAP in services. Working hard with teams to ensure operational targets are achieved.
- Conducting periodic analysis of profitability of operations and devising plans for improving profitability and reducing costs. Preparing periodical revenue and collection forecast for the unit.
- Identifying training needs of the personnel and conducting regular trainings, updating on latest government and hospital policies.
- Resolving patients and staff complaints in a diplomatic manner. Ensuring patient's and family's rights are been taken care of.
- Any other responsibility as deemed fit from time to time.

Assistant Manager Operations

HCG Cancer Centre, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India (July 2016 – September 2017) Serving as the Head of the Billing Department for the centre, monitoring, developing and maintaining all billing procedures as per the funding sources. Analysing trends and performance through the statistics for betterment of services and procedures. Closely monitoring feedback from service users and colleagues to present the same to the management team to analyse the satisfaction and quality Indices.

- Liaising and coordinating with various hospital departments, clinical and nonclinical ensuring smooth functioning of daily billing activities.
- Regular visits and written communication with corporate clients, meetings for the concerns including payments, patient comfort and closure of the queries before end date.
- Closely monitoring cash and credit billing departments. Making sure the processes are being done as per set SOPs of the organization.
- Responsible for providing adequate support and resources to ensure trouble-free operations of the billing department (IPD, OPD, Diagnostic and Day-care billing).
- Conduct daily, weekly and monthly review meetings with billing teams to review performance, GAPs of previous month, targets for the new month and forming action plans for better outcomes.

- Ensuring quality of services given are equivalent to the set standards, analysing the GAP in services. Working hard with teams to ensure operational targets are achieved.
- Liaising with marketing team, ensuring smooth coordination of corporate relations.
- Conducting periodic analysis of profitability of operations and devising plans for improving profitability and reducing costs. Preparing periodical revenue and collection forecast for the unit.
- Identifying training needs of the personnel and conducting regular trainings, updating on latest government and hospital policies.
- Resolving patients and staff complaints in a diplomatic manner. Ensuring patient's and family's rights are been taken care of.
- Any other responsibility as deemed fit from time to time.

Customer Care Assistant

Columbia Asia Hospital (January 2015 – June 2016)

Reporting to the Customer Care Manager for all the concerns and reports. Working in front/back office (reception area), acting as first point of contact for all the visitors/patients as well as for all the other internal departments.

- Counselling patient and relatives for Admission / Discharge policy including Cashless and insurance guidelines.
- Guiding patients for all health check-up packages and about all other available services.
- Preparing / Auditing IP/OP patient bill.
- Playing an instrumental role as the single point of contact for all service users and patients, effectively managing patient appointments and dealing with any queries in an efficient and knowledgeable manner.
- Working closely with other members of the team in achieving common goals and monitoring all the quality indicators which involves waiting time targets (patient registration, OPD, admission, discharge, room transfers, pharmacy, telephonic conversation, pt. reports management).
- Taking active part with marketing department in marketing campaigns and promoting new as well as existing hospital services / packages.
- Maintaining high level of discipline and hospitality with utmost sincerity.
- Helping colleagues with flexible support at all times to maintain smooth running of the operations.
- Preparing all the excel sheet at the end of the day to monitor the performance indicator and emailing the data to senior management which includes patient feedback forms, waiting times, grooming standard of the employees, IP & OP stats, as well as other patients (Radiology, X-ray, Lab, ER footfall)
- Taking feedback from CC Manager on daily / weekly / monthly basis to find out the areas
 of improvement and for analysing gap in service.
- Monitoring all facilities across the hospital and reporting concerns to the facility manager.

Team Administrator

The Royal Marsden Hospital NHS Trust /

Sutton & Merton Community Services, London (Nov 2012 – Nov 2013)

Working in central administration department to facilitate all the services across the community, coordinating with individual clinical teams on the initiative of providing quality service and support to patients across various sites of the trust.

- Responsible for the provision of cross cover at other sites of the trust when required.
- Working as a proactive member of the administration and clinical teams responsible for the provision of a high quality patient-centred care across the trust.
- Playing an instrumental role as the single point of contact for all service users and patients, effectively managing patient appointments and dealing with any queries in an efficient and knowledgeable manner.
- Working closely with other members of the team in achieving common goals and monitoring referral waiting time targets for the patients.
- Regularly liaising with diverse clinical and administrative teams across the trust and updating clinicians (HCP) and patients for relevant information as well as maintaining high level of confidentiality.
- Providing flexible support and contribution to the service improvement projects as well as maintaining and monitoring patient's data on the information systems.
- Promoting equality, diversity, confidentiality and team working ethics under all the circumstances and putting patients at the heart of every decision.
- Identifying any patient concerns and escalating the same to a member of the senior management team.
- Undertaking the effective management of patient appointments as well as monitoring and gathering patient/service user feedback for the service improvement projects.

Bank Administrator / Health-Care Assistant (Dual role)

The Whittington Hospital NHS, London (Aug 2012 – September 2014)

Working flexibly with the administration and clinical areas to facilitate day to day activities.

- Working flexibly with the administration, clinical and care areas to facilitate day to day activities, providing high quality patient centred care and ensuring all patient needs and requirements are consistently satisfied.
- Primarily working as a Healthcare Assistant, developing excellent working relationships with both colleagues and patients and ensuring care is provided in a safe and comfortable environment that promotes respect, privacy and dignity under all the circumstances.

Health-Care Assistant

Ivelhurst Nursing Home, Somerset, UK (Aug 2011 – Dec 2012)

Providing assistance to the service users and maintaining their daily clinical documentations.

- Personally responsible for the efficient delivery of care to service users, monitoring and maintaining patients' daily clinical documentation and coordinating admission and discharge planning activities.
- Undertaking the effective management and monitoring of all general and clinical appointments.
- Constantly working to improve patients living, encouraging them through undertaking and planning different activities according to the needs of an individual service user.

Hotel & Restaurant Manager

RK Hotel & Garden Restaurant (August 2008 – May 2011)

Responsible for the day-to-day business operations. Accountability for budgeting and marketing, financial management, planning, organising and directing all hotel services, including front-of-house (reception, concierge, reservations), food and beverage operations, and housekeeping.

Taking a strategic overview and planning ahead to maximise profits, paying attention to the details, setting the example for staff to deliver a standard of service and presentation that meets guests needs and expectations.

- Promoting and marketing the business, analysing sales figures and devising marketing and revenue management strategies.
- Managing budgets and financial plans as well as controlling expenditure, maintaining statistical and financial records.
- Setting and achieving sales and profit targets.
- Recruiting, training and monitoring staff, planning work schedules for individuals and teams.
- Dealing with customer complaints and comments, addressing problems and troubleshooting.
- Ensuring events and conferences run smoothly.
- Supervising maintenance, supplies, renovations and furnishings, dealing with contractors and suppliers, also ensuring security is effective.
- Carrying out inspections of property and services, ensuring compliance with licensing laws, health and safety and other statutory regulations.

Sales Executive

HDFC Bank Ltd. India (August 2007 – June 2008)

Managing client portfolio, delivering quality services under all circumstances. Giving guidance and support to the clients about new as well as existing products and services, helping them getting started with the services, continuing lifetime flexible support and building healthy working relationship.

OTHER QUALIFICATIONS / ATTRIBUTES

ECDL Advanced Qualification – Includes IT user fundamentals, Security for IT users, Improving productivity using IT, DBMS software, MS-Office package (European Computer Driving Licence - 2014)

Certified Industrial Accountant+
The Institute of Computer Accountants (ICA)

Entrepreneurship Development + Computer Hardware Skill Formation Training Program Sponsored by Government of Gujarat India.

Excellent user: MS-Office package, IT - Internet tools and applications.

References

Mr. Damodaran TK
Sr. Manager Corporate,
Health Care Global (HCG)
801-07, Sun Square Building,
Nr. Nest Hotel, Off C. G. Road,
Navrangpura, Ahmedabad. Gujarat,
India. 380007.
Email: damodaran@hcghospitals.in

Email: damodaran@ncgnospita

Ms. Sandhya Patel
Temporary Staffing Officer,
The Whittington Hospital NHS
Trust, Magdala Avenue,
Islington,
London, England, N19 5NF
Email: sandhya.patel2@nhs.net
Ph.: 0207 2885325

Mr. Srinivas U Menon Customer Care Manager, **Columbia Asia Hospital**, Off S G Highway, Thaltej - hebatpur road, Ahmedabad. Gujarat, India. 380054. Email: srinivas.m@columbiaasia.com Ph.: +91 79 39 8989 69

Ms. Marie Coogan Administration Team Leader, Sutton & Merton Community Services, NHS Trust, Cranmer Road, Mitcham, London, England, SE13 7SZ Email: Marie.Coogan@smcs.nhs.uk Ph.:0208 544 2002